那么  你有什么事
So, what did you want?
现在太迟了
It's too late now.
什么太迟了
Too late for what?
我以后再告诉你
I'll tell you later.
说吧  铃声才刚响过
Come on, the bell just rang.
咱们还有时间
We still got time.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
你确定吗
You sure?
是的
Yeah.
为什么是现在  突然改主意了
Why now, all of a sudden?
怎么  你不再想要了吗
What, you don't want to anymore?
我当然想要
Yeah, I do.
我只是奇怪你为什么改主意了
I'm just wondering what changed your mind.
因为你
You did.
现在吗
Now?
如果你想要的话
If you want.
抱歉打扰了
Excuse me.
你们俩跟我来
You two need to come with me.
-坐下  -但我们没有...
- Take a seat. - But we didn't--
你们明知不该到那后边去的
You know you're not supposed to be back there.
我们什么都没做
We weren't doing anything.
在我看来可不是这样
That's not what it looked like to me.
菲尔德校长
Principal Fields will be back
开完校会就回来
as soon as the assembly is over.
沃什本太太  求您了
Ms. Washburn, please,
如果我再被记过  我妈
if I get one more referral, my mom--
坐到长椅上
Bench.
谁在她头上动土了
Who put sand in her vagina?
孩子们
Kids.
你们好吗
How you boys doing?
我们能帮你什么忙吗
Uh, can we help you?
我当然希望你们能帮上忙
I certainly hope so.
你知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
手提电脑
A laptop?
是台加密的手提电脑
Password-protected laptop
需要你们这些书呆子破解
that I need you nerds to hack into.
没有杀虫剂  也没有有毒清洁剂
No insecticides or toxic cleaners.
检查一下浴室
Check the bathroom.
你们是谁
Who are you?
你们室友的医生
Your roommate's doctor.
还记得你们的室友吧
You remember your roommate, don't you?
我以为他不过是得了支气管炎
I thought he just had bronchitis.
那是罗斯格校医中心的
That's what the morons
那帮白痴的想法
at the Rutgers Student Medical Center thought,
也许这也是他把肺都咳出来的原因之一
which may be part of the reason he just coughed up a lung.
你什么意思  他把肺都咳出来了吗
What do you mean, he coughed up a lung?
他不停地咳嗽...
He coughed...
直到他把自己胸腔内的
after which the respiratory organ
呼吸器官都咳到嘴里了...
which resided in his chest resided in his mouth...
实际上  是他手上
Actually, his hand.
先到嘴里  然后手上
Well, his mouth, then his hand.
卧室没问题
Bathroom's clean.
这里面是什么
What's in this?
苏打水
Just soda.
-介意我喝点吗  -你想喝我的饮料吗
- Mind if I have some? - You want my drink?
有意见吗
You got a problem with that?
当然
Uh, yeah.
确实有意见
Actually, I do.
你们闯进我们的宿舍
You barge into our room,
开始检查我们的私人物品
start looking through our personal, private stuff,
逼我侵入一台手提电脑
demand I hack into a computer
我想我能肯定这不属于
I think I can safely assume doesn't belong--
抱歉  我打断你说话了吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Did I break your concentration?
请继续
Please continue.
你刚才说到了隐私
You were talking about personal privacy.
怎么  你说完了吗
What, you're finished?
那好  轮到我了
Well, allow me to retort.
等等
Wait a second.
你说的都是真实事件吗
You're saying this actually happened?
当然了
Absolutely.
你撒谎
You're lying.
有意思  你能证明吗
Interesting theory. Can you prove it?
医生不持枪
Doctors don't carry guns.
他们不会射杀别人
They don't shoot people,
而且他们也不会搜查病人的家
and they definitely don't search patients' homes.
况且  我看过《低俗小说》
Plus, I've seen Pulp Fiction--
你就是在扒电影情节
the movie you're totally ripping off.
等等  是蒂米·摩根吗
Wait, uh, was it Timmy Morgan?
-我不知道  -肯定是他
- I have no idea. - It had to be him.
他就痴迷于老电影
He's, like, totally obsessed with old movies.
《低俗小说》可不是老电影  什么
Pulp Fiction is not an old mov--what?
所以你来这里
So you're here to talk
是向校长告蒂米的状吗
to the principal about something Timmy did?
我对蒂米没意见
I got no problem with Timmy.
就算有的话  我也不会打小报告
And even if I did, I ain't no snitch.
那你来这干什么
Then why are you here?
为自己解决麻烦
To dig myself out of a hole.
结果给自己惹了更大的麻烦
Instead I dug a bigger one.
你干了什么
What'd you do?
你的眼睛怎么了
What happened to your eye?
与你无关
It's none of your business.
实际上  与你才无关  我是医生
Actually, it's none of yours. I'm a doctor.
已经伤了几天了
It's a few days old,
所以不是你们在这里的原因
so that's not why you're here,
除非你俩是因为密谋报仇被抓来的
unless you two got busted for some sort of revenge plot.
但那样的话  你们应该生气而非羞愧
But then you'd look angry instead of...ashamed.
我才没有羞愧
I'm not ashamed.
有意思
Interesting.
你还嘴硬  声称不羞愧
You defensively insist that you're not ashamed,
当然  这更证明你很羞愧
which, of course, means you are ashamed.
但是  你却是受害者
And yet, you're the victim.
你想知道她的黑眼圈怎么来的吗
You want to know how she got the black eye?
先告诉我们你在这里的原因
Tell us why you're here first.
有人说过你很烦人吗
Anyone ever tell you you're annoying?
没有
No.
有  他一直被这么说
Yes, all the time.
但他说的对
But he's right.
想知道吗  你先说
You want to know? You first.
我没有杀人
I didn't kill anybody.
我必须来这演讲  所以我假想
I have to be here, so I figured
我的开场得华丽些
I'd punch up the stakes in the first act.
但我们确实  而且总是
But we did, and almost always do,
检查病人家里
search the patient's home.
如果我们事先告诉他们的话
And if we tell them first,
他们就会把一些东西藏起来
then they can hide something that we need to know
我们就无从知晓他们生了什么病
in order to figure out what's wrong with them.
他们为什么要把潜在的"杀手"藏起来呢
Why would they hide something that could be killing them?
因为他们是傻子
Because they are morons.
他们都是白痴  每个人都撒谎
They're all morons, and everybody lies.
等等  如果每个人都撒谎的话
Wait, if everybody lies,
那就意味着你现在也在撒谎
then that means you're lying right now.
我没说每个人总在撒谎  亚里士多德
I didn't say everybody always lies...Aristotle.
话已至此  如果没有问题
And on that note, unless there are any questions...
很好
Good.
豪拉尼医生
Oh, Dr. Hourani...
在您结束前
Before you finish,
也许您能描述一下您的本职工作
maybe you could describe what you actually do.
比如有人来医院做常规检查
You know, like if someone comes in for a routine physical?
你想让我谈常规工作吗
You want routine?
是的
Please.
感觉像是  有点麻
It just feels kind of, like, numb.
你经常骑自行车吗
You do a lot of bicycle riding?
没有
No.
你结婚多长时间了
How long have you been married?
下个月就十二年了
It's 12 years next month.
你有六个孩子
You have six kids.
你不是觉得生孩子
Well, you don't think it could have
跟这个有关系吧
anything to do with that, do you?
也许吧
Probably.
你多久用一次按摩棒
How often do you use your vibrator?
你说什么
Excuse me?
就是你那电动的小布拉德·彼特
Your battery-operated Brad Pitt.
在你生了
After giving the gift of life
六个八公斤的肉球以后
to six eight-pound, four-ounce wrecking balls,
我应该可以假设
I think I can safely assume
你改用工业加强版了吧
it's an industrial-strength model?
豪拉尼医生  别这样
Dr. Hourani, please.
是你想听我说日常工作的
You wanted routine.
我能结束了吗
Am I done?
也许我们该往下继续了
Maybe we should just move on.
没问题
No problem.
我是说继续介绍你的日常工作
I meant with your typical day.
我想你每天应该会诊不止一个病人吧
I assume you see more than one patient?
就一个
Nope.
好吧
Okay.
那么该我们的下一位来宾了
Then I guess we will move on to our next guest.
等等  如果你每天只看一个病人
Wait, if you only see one patient,
剩余时间你都干什么
what do you do the rest of the day?
豪拉尼医生
Dr. Hourani?
正好是午饭时间
Just in time for lunch.
如果你说的午饭是和董事会开电话会议
By lunch, you mean a conference call with the board,
正好是指我已经迟到二十分钟了的话
and by just in time, you mean, 20 minutes late.
我说的午饭是指
I meant sex...
做爱
by lunch.
我们从上汤菊花开始怎么样
How about we start with a small tossed salad?
那从今早开始  我节食
As of this morning, I'm on a diet.
什么意思
Meaning?
我说了  我很忙
I told you, I'm busy.
不  你告诉我你二十分钟前
No, you told me you were supposed to be busy
应该很忙
20 minutes ago.
但很明显你能把事情往后推
But you were obviously able to put them off then,
那你现在也可以继续推
there's no reason you can't put them off now.
换个说法吧  我那时想延后
How about, "I wanted to then,
但现在不想了
and now I don't"?
把你的手指从我电话上拿开
Get your finger off my phone.
显然有些事我们需要讨论一下
We obviously have something we need to discuss.
时机不对
Now is not a good time.
如果你生气是因为觉得
If you're mad because you don't feel
你没有感受到我表达出的爱慕之情
you're getting the necessary amount of affection,
直说就是了
all you have to do is ask.
说真的  现在不行
Seriously, not now.
如果我没记错  周日的早午餐不错
If memory serves, I enjoyed a healthy Sunday brunch.
所以你是在暗示
So your insinuation--
-你有什么问题啊  -你
- What is your problem? - You!
你就是我的问题
You are my problem.
你是这星球上最自私
You are the most selfish, self-centered son of a bitch
最我行我素的混蛋
on the face of the planet.
我受不了了
And I'm sick of it.
我  受够了
I'm just...done.
我没办法再忍你了
I can't deal with you anymore.
这就是一位平凡的医生平常的一天
So that's what a typical doctor does on a typical day.
还有问题吗
Any questions?
按摩棒是什么
What's a vibrator?
你女朋友为什么生气
Why was your girlfriend so mad?
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
显然那很重要
Well, obviously it matters.
我是说如果她是你女朋友
I mean, if she's your girlfriend,
你应该在乎她的感受
you should care how she feels.
我是说那与故事无关
I mean, it doesn't matter to the story.
这是故事里最重要的部分了
It's the most important part of the story.
这是唯一重要的部分
It's the only thing that does matter.
你没有经常吻她  这是问题所在吗
You don't kiss her enough -- is that the problem?
绝对不是
Absolutely not.
按你的逻辑  就是这原因了
Which, by your definition, means it is.
我们经常接吻
We kiss plenty.
该你了
Your turn.
那是什么原因
Then what's the problem?
该你了
Your turn.
是什么原因
What's the problem?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
校长到底什么时候回来
When exactly will the commandant be back?
不会太久了  先生
Shouldn't be much longer, sir.
然后呢
Well?
现在你就打算不说话了
Oh, so now you're not gonna talk.
你真是太成熟了
That's real mature.
好吧
All right, fine.
我们在学校后面接吻时被抓了
We got busted for kissing behind the school.
现在你知道为什么我们在这了
Now you know why we're here.
告诉我们你在这里的原因
So tell us why you're here.
交易是关于她那黑眼圈的由来
The deal was about the black eye.
而且我们也没亲上
And we didn't kiss.
你只是想让他求你  是吗
So you were just making him beg, huh?
没看出来你喜欢欲迎还拒
I didn't have you pegged as a tease.
我不是那种人
I'm not a tease.
现有证据表明你就是
The available evidence suggests otherwise.
我才不欲迎还拒
I'm not a tease.
证明一下
Prove it...
把你们的故事告诉我
By--by telling me your story.
你这可悲的失败者  混蛋
You're a pathetic loser, jerk!
就算我得了脑癌  而你的嘴唇是唯一的
And I wouldn't kiss you if I had brain cancer
治疗方法  我也不会亲你的
and your lips were the cure!
她真这么说的吗
She actually said that?
没错  大概是两天前
Well, yeah, that was, like, two days ago.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
我显然没引诱他或怎么样
I clearly didn't lead him along or anything like that,
这就证明我没有欲迎还拒
which proves I'm not a tease.
回到正题  你女朋友为什么生你气
So why is your girlfriend mad at you?
我感受到了一种御姐气场
I'm getting a kind of bossy vibe.
我猜你就好这一口
I take it you're into that.
别回答他
Don't answer!
该你了
Your turn.
你有什么不舒服吗  先生
What seems to be the problem, sir?
我呼吸越来越困难了
I'm having more difficulty breathing
胸口有点疼
and some pain in my chest.
你是新来的  对吗
You're new, aren't you?
没错  我刚从芝加哥来
Uh, yeah, I just moved from Chicago.
芝加哥很棒  你从哪个区来的
Chicago's awesome. What part are you from?
我们得做胸部CT
We need to get a chest C.T.
等一下  我才是这个团队里的老大
Excuse me, I'm the senior team member,
这意味着只有我说要做什么
which means we don't need anything
我们才做什么
unless I say we need it.
你想来段婚外情吗
Do you want to have an affair?
你想来次三人行吗
You want to have a threesome?
你们不能这么跟她说话  我要去告诉卡迪
You can't talk to her like that. I'm telling Cuddy.
我们要做胸部CT
We need a chest C.T.
自己做去
Get it yourself.
那是不是叫作性骚扰
Isn't that, like, sexual harassment?
如果你长得帅就没事
Not if you're good-looking.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你说其中一个身材矮小鼻子很大
You said the one guy was short with a big nose.
估计那不仅是他全身唯一大的地方
Guess that's not the only thing that's big.
什么意思
What does that mean?
就是说他又在撒谎
It means he's lying... again.
因为你无法承受事情真相
Because you can't handle the truth!
这太简单了
That's so easy.
《义海雄风》
A Few Good Men.
好吧  我放弃了
Okay, I give up.
我觉得我们该有请
I think we should move on
下一位来宾了
to our next guest.
德赖登先生...
Mr. Dryden...
为纽约最大的广告代理公司之一
Uh, works for one of the largest advertising agencies
-工作  -无聊  无聊
- in New York City. - Boring! Boring!
我们能不能至少知道那病人怎么了
Can we at least hear what happened to the patient?
是啊  拜托
Yeah, please.
如果豪拉尼医生保证
If Dr. Hourani promises to--
病人死了
Patient's dead.
归你了  唐
Floor is yours, Don.
是戴夫
Dave.
他没死
He's not dead.
你前面还说他尚在医院
You said earlier he was still in the hospital.
-他怎么了  -他不停咳嗽
- What's wrong with him? - He's got a cough.
你说他把肺咳出来了
You said he coughed up a lung.
-那手提电脑呢  -谁关心电脑啊
- What about the laptop? - Who cares about the laptop?
对啊   而且他都说了那是骗人的
Yeah, and he already said he was lying about that,
你个傻子
you moron.
盖布
Gabe...
-在这里我们不能这样说话  -他就说了啊
- We do not use that word here. - He did.
没错  我说的就是你这种人
Yeah, and I was talking about people like you.
豪拉尼医生  拜托了
Dr. Hourani, please,
能不能请你尽快把故事讲完  好让我们继续
could you just finish, quickly, so we can move on?
我不知道是哪里出了问题
I don't know what's wrong.
刚才情况还很稳定  突然间就
He was stable for a while, and then all of a sudden, he just--
支气管感染肯定是
Bronchial infection must be
由耐药菌株引起的
from a drug-resistant strain.
血氧饱和度正急速下降
O-2 sats are plummeting.
我们得在他呼吸停止前
We need to get him on a bronchodilator
给他安上支气管扩张器
before he goes into respiratory arrest.
准备吸引  帮他坐直了
Suction, sit him up.
开始吹氧
Start blow by oxygen.
那是什么
What is that?
我觉得是他的
I think it's his...
他的肺
It's his lung.
真有这事儿吗
That actually happened?
没错  确有此事
Yes, it really happened.
我通常接手其他医生无法诊断的病例
I take cases that other doctors fail to diagnose,
所以每次只接一个
which is why I only take one at a time.
眼下  我的病人是名大学生
My current patient is a college student.
现在正躺在医院里
He's actually in the hospital right now.
并且  他确实咳出了很大一部分
And, yes, he really did cough up a large portion
肺部的坏死组织
of dead lung tissue.
怎么会有这种事
How's that even possible?
她就是这么问的
That's what she said.
确实  一字不差
No, she did literally say that.
怎么会有这种事
How's that even possible?
原发性鳞状细胞癌会从根本上
Primary squamous carcinoma could cause
瓦解肺部组织
lung tissue to basically disintegrate.
这不是癌症  支气管镜结果正常
It's not cancer. F.O.B. was normal.
也不是感染
It's not an infection either.
广谱抗生素不起作用
Broad-spectrum antibiotics haven't had any effect.
谁会给放在上锁的办公室
Who password-protects a computer
上锁的抽屉里的手提电脑加密啊
they keep in a locked desk in a locked office?
他的同事中一定有人认为
Someone who works with someone who thinks it's okay
私闯他人住宅是合理的
to break into other people's homes?
阿米巴肝脓肿可以穿过横膈膜
An amebic liver abscess could rupture
损坏胸部器官
through the diaphragm into the thorax.
但他的肝功能测试结果全部正常
Not when his liver-function tests are all normal.
他的室友是计算机科学专业的
His dorm mates are computer science majors.
如果他们在制作芯片  就有可能
If they're fabricating chips, they could be working
接触各种有毒溶剂
with all kinds of different toxic solvents.
我们得去检查宿舍
We need to search the dorm.
"我们"吗
"We"?
没错  我们走吧[法语]
Oui. Allons-y.
我们外出期间
While we're out,
做个胸腔镜肺活检
do a thorascopic lung biopsy
以及c-ANCA化验
and a c-ANCA,
因为这是结节病
because it's sarcoidosis.
可如果你觉得这是结节病  那为什么
But if you think it's sarcoidosis, why are you...
所以你确实逼迫他室友
So you really did force his roommate
侵入了手提电脑
to hack into the laptop?
骗你们干什么
Why would I lie?
那这是谁的电脑
But whose laptop is it?
是你女朋友的电脑  对吧
It's your girlfriend's, isn't it?
她不是我女朋友
She's not my girlfriend.
我对她感兴趣  因为她是客户
I'm just interested in her because she's a client,
而且她睡在床单以上
and she sleeps above her covers--
四英尺以上
four feet above her covers.
什么
What?
语出《捉鬼敢死队》
Ghostbusters.
所以她才这么生气
So that's why she's so mad--
因为你偷看了她的电脑
you looked through her computer?
错  电脑的事发生在她生气以后
No, that part happened after she got mad.
她生气在先
First she got mad.
然后我才偷她电脑想解决问题
Then I stole her computer to fix things.
最后才接手病例
And then we got the case.
等等  你偷她的电脑
Wait, so you tried to fix your relationship
是为了跟她和好吗
by stealing her computer?
你这么说
Well, when you say it like that...
是没错
Yes.
听起来你才是个傻子
Looks like you're the moron.
我还能从那里弄到三副高尔夫球杆
I can also get three sets of golf clubs in there.
别扯了
No way.
你才没有为了拿到电脑
You didn't get her laptop
而轰倒她的办公室大门
by blowing down the door of her office.
那是《霹雳炮与飞毛腿》里的情节
That's from Thunderbolt and Lightfoot.
我就是想看看你有没有开小差
Just seeing if you're still paying attention.
其实我更狡猾
It was actually more subtle.
《龙凤斗智》
The Thomas Crown Affair--
史蒂夫．麦奎因主演的那部
the Steve McQueen version.
-拜托别再骗我们了  -不好意思
- Just tell us the truth already. - Excuse me.
在座还有其他人
But there are others here
希望能有机会说上几句
who would like a chance to speak.
来吧
Go right ahead.
不要
No!
观众的眼睛是雪亮的
Audience is always right.
卢克
Luke.
不是我
It wasn't me.
太太  你还好吗
Ma'am, are you okay?
能听见我说话吗
Can you hear me?
什么味道啊
Ooh, what's that smell?
闻着像瓦斯泄漏
Smells like a gas leak.
通知卡迪医生
Call Dr. Cuddy.
你给一屋子的病人投毒
You poisoned a room full of patients
就为了偷你女朋友的电脑吗
so you could steal your girlfriend's laptop?
我没给任何人投毒
I didn't poison anybody.
我就是在地板上洒了点硫化氢和氨
I spilled some hydrogen sulfide and ammonia on the floor,
我想这股恶臭铁定能把所有人都熏跑
thinking the stench would clear the place out.
但有些白痴为了不闻恶臭
But instead of breathing through his nose,
屏住呼吸
some idiot decided to hold his breath.
就昏了过去  而且很快
He passes out, and before I know it,
那里便成了集体癔症发作的好地方
the place is a perfect storm of mass hysteria...
但这计划还是很成功
Although it worked out just as well.
他们都是傻子
They're morons.
同意
Agreed.
不  我说的不是病人  是那些小孩
No, not the patients, the kids.
你怎么偷的根本无关紧要
It doesn't matter how you stole it.
重要的是为什么
What matters is why.
知道吗  你让我想起了一个人
You know, you're starting to remind me of someone.
我没问你怎么偷的  我问你为什么要偷
I didn't ask how you stole it. I asked why.
还不够明显吗
Isn't it obvious?
你觉得你看了她的预算表
You think you can tell why she's mad
还有每日行程
by reading budget spreadsheets
就能知道她为什么生气了吗
and per diem schedules?
我知道她为什么生气
I know why she's mad.
我需要知道的是怎样才能让她不生气
What I need to know is how to make her un-mad.
第一步就是
And step one is gaining access
看她电脑里的日记
to the journal on her laptop,
那记录着她最内心的想法
where she records her innermost thoughts...
而不只是和我一起看毛片时的想法
Instead of just watching porn with me.
行了  成年人
Oh, grow up.
如果毛片很糟糕  那里边怎么有那么多修女
If porn was bad, why would there be so many nuns in it?
她为什么生气
Why is she mad?
因为我是我
I was myself,
顺便说一句
which, by the way,
她应该无条件地爱我的全部
she's supposed to love unconditionally.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
我们过了个不错的周末
We had a great weekend.
去了家蓝调俱乐部
Went to a Blues club,
用影碟机看了《煤炭工狂想曲》
we watched Cinderfella on DVD.
还有呢
And?
这不是重点
It doesn't matter.
她无理取闹  我得想办法解决
She's being unreasonable, and I have to fix it.
我需要知道什么对她很重要
I need to know what's really important to her.
-一些重要的事情  -因为
- I need something big. - Because?
我们跳过吧
We're past that.
你试过她童年时期宠物的名字没有
Have you tried childhood pet names?
我又不认识她的宠物
I don't know her pets.
她从来没提过她的宠物吗
She's never mentioned a pet?
好吧  提过  但我左耳进右耳就出了
Well, yeah, but I wasn't listening.
她生气又不是
She's not mad
因为我不记得一条死狗的名字
because I don't remember a dead dog's name.
她第一只狗叫罗纳尔多
Her first dog was Ronaldo.
是R-o还是R-e-y
Is that R-o or R-e-y?
我没问  俩都试试
I didn't ask. Try both.
刚从急诊室接到个病例
Just got a case from the E.R.
罗斯格的学生
Rutgers student came in
有类似急性支气管炎的病症
with what looked like acute bronchitis.
但他的血液和痰培养里什么都没发现
But there's nothing in his blood or sputum cultures.
你不觉得是时候你们黑人
Don't you think it's time you people
停止指望白人替你们解决所有难题了吗
stop looking to the white man to solve all your problems?
他的血饱和氧量太低了
His O-2 sats are in the toilet.
要是再找不出是什么攻击他的
If we don't figure out what's attacking his--
那就去找出来
So figure it out!
我忙着呢
I'm busy.
这肯定不可能
That can't be true.
为嘛
Why not?
因为如果他真快死了  你可是个医生
'Cause if he was dying-- I mean, you're a doctor.
每天都有病人死
Patients die every day.
不是每个病例都有意思
Not all of them are interesting.
两个问题你还是一个都没有回答
You still haven't answered either question.
她生气是因为她的基因决定了
She was mad because she's genetically programmed
她会小题大做每件小事
to make a big deal out of every little thing.
所以她生气是因为她是个女的
So she's mad 'cause she's a girl.
现在她生气了是因为她的基因决定了
And now she's mad because she's programmed
她也会小题大做每件小事
to make a big deal out of every little thing.
其实  她不是那样的
Actually, she's not like that.
你为啥还替她说话
Why are you sticking up for her?
她说你是个可悲的混蛋而且还讨厌你
She says you're a pathetic jerk and she hates you.
那是很久以前了
That was a long time ago.
是两天前
It was two days ago.
而且她那时候说的又不是真心话
And it wasn't even true then.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我知道你心里的想法
Because I know how you think.
真的吗
Really?
真的
Really.
真的吗
Really?
亲脸可不算
Uh, and no peck on the cheek.
必须得亲嘴
It has to be on the lips.
赌赢了好让她亲你
Winning a bet to force her to kiss you
这其实违背了你自己关于
actually cuts against your theory
你知道她咋想的理论
that you know how she thinks.
我没有逼她做任何
I wasn't forcing her to do anything
她不愿做的事
that she didn't want to do.
你将来是想去NBA还是NFL发展
You're hoping for a career in the NBA or the NFL?
那个赌只是让她做了她想做的
The bet let her do what she wanted to do
同时又能装作很不乐意的样子
while still being able to act like she didn't,
所以她的朋友才不会  像是
so her friends wouldn't get all, like,
叫她荡妇什么的
calling her a slut or something.
再说这也没什么荡不荡的
Not that it's slutty or anything.
就是个吻而已
It's just a kiss.
完全是胡扯
Not even close to true.
我只是不相信我会输
I just couldn't believe I'd lose.
现在我们有点眉目了
Ah, now we're getting somewhere.
不  我们没有
No, we're not.
我以为我们有点了呢
Oh, I thought we were.
不  你知道我们没有头绪
No, you thought we weren't,
这就是你的目的
and that's exactly what you want,
因为你不愿意告诉我们她为什么生你的气
because you don't want to tell us why was she mad at you!
你说你连自己的工作都不想做
You tell us you don't want to do your job
就是因为忙着黑进
because you're too busy trying to break
你女朋友的电脑好找到个法子
into your girlfriend's laptop to figure out a way
让她不生你的气了
to make her not mad at you.
但你却不肯告诉我们
But you don't tell us
她到底为什么生你的气
why she was mad at you.
那太蠢了
It's stupid.
说
Talk.
我走了
I'm out of here.
除非
Unless...
瑞秋马上就该醒了
Rachel's gonna be up soon.
你怎么知道呢
Well, you never know.
我就是知道
Yes, I do.
走之前把垃圾带出去好吗
Can you take the garbage out before you go?
我倒是想啊  但是
Uh, I-I-I would, but...
拜托
Oh, come on.
又不是很多
It's not a lot.
早上腿总是很疼嘛
Pain's always worst first thing in the morning.
妈咪
Mommy!
你用了她的牙刷
You used her toothbrush?
这也太恶心了
That's so gross.
有什么大不了的
What's the big deal?
前一晚互换口水的时候
It's not like she had a problem
也没见她有什么意见
swapping spit the night before.
也许她在乎的不是牙刷上有你的口水
Well, maybe it's not the swapping spit that bothers her,
而是你根本不在意她说过的话
but the fact that you don't listen to her.
她跟你说过别这样做吗
Had she warned you not to do it?
我在意她说的话
Oh, I listen to her.
可你刚刚才说你不在意
But you just said before that you didn't.
不  我说的是我不记得她说什么了
No, I said I didn't remember what she said.
不对  你说的就是你不在意
No, you said you don't listen--
我在意她说的话
I listen to her.
成不
Okay?
相信我  我在意
Believe me, I listen.
那是我的牙刷
It's my toothbrush,
而且不只一次了
and it's not just once.
并不是说我多介意你用我的牙刷
And it's not like I'd even care,
但你也不能彻底把它给糟践了呀
but you totally destroy it.
你本来是应该用它来刷牙的
You're supposed to brush with it,
不是当磨牙骨头一样咬着玩
not gnaw on it like a rawhide bone.
我认为四蛀牙小姐应该
I think Miss Four Cavities' time
多花时间学学无蛀牙先生
would be better spent copying Mr. No Cavities
而不是批评他
instead of complaining about him.
考虑到我刚才做的事
And given what I'd just been doing,
我觉得你肯定也不想我出去吃饭的时候
I thought you wouldn't want me going out to dinner
嘴里有口臭牙上有韭菜
without a good brush and a floss.
麻烦请你就用我给你买的那把牙刷行吗
Would you please just use the toothbrush I bought you?
麻烦请你闭上嘴好好看电影行吗
Would you please just shut up and watch the movie?
我说了"请"
I said, "Please."
你干嘛非得
Why would you have to
在晚饭之前刷牙
brush your teeth before you go to dinner?
你不会想知道的
You don't want to know...
至少现在不想
Yet.
你真恶心  而且蠢
You're gross and dumb.
你听她说话
You listen to what she says
只是为了告诉她她错得离谱
just so you can tell her how wrong she is.
你又傻又天真
You are clueless and naive.
我必须得告诉她她错了
I have to tell her that she's wrong,
因为我不说就没人会说了
'cause no one else will.
她是院长
She's the boss,
也就是说她周围全是白痴
which means she's surrounded by morons
那些人不是怕她的
who are either afraid of her,
就是想拍她马屁的
or they want to kiss up to her,
要不就是想
or they want to...
亲她的
kiss her.
但你不是
But not you.
我已经亲过她了
I already kissed her.
而且我很尊重她  所以才不会把她
And I respect her enough not to treat her
当成弱不禁风的小花朵一样供着
like some tender blossom who needs to be coddled.
我懂
Makes sense to me.
你当时就是抱着这种想法吗
That's what you think you did?
是啊  必须的
Yeah, totally.
你是说
You mean...
什么
Wha--
是你
You?
不是  我没有打她
No, I didn't punch her.
你个白痴
You're a moron.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean to.
我那根棍子长得很诡异
The stick had wicked heel curve.
我说过你是个白痴了吗
Did I mention you're a moron?
刚才是你说的把你
Okay, you just said it's wrong
女朋友当成弱者对待是不对的
to treat your girlfriend like she's weaker than you.
我说的又不是得不得分
I'm not talking about trying to score.
我是在说你打那么高干啥
I'm talking about shooting high.
就跟穿网球鞋走木地板一样傻
Tennis shoes on a wooden floor?
往她两腿中间打  不就接不住了
She obviously can't butterfly and cover the low corners.
该你了
Your turn.
电脑怎么样了
The laptop.
我肯定是因为局部癫痫产生幻觉了
I must be in the midst of a complex partial seizure,
你怎么会坐在我办公桌前
'cause I know you are not sitting at my desk.
不好意思  我办公室里没有润肤露了
Sorry. Ran out of lotion in mine.
你给我出去
Get the hell out of here.
不行  这是唯一一个
Can't. This is the only place left
我能呆着而卡迪又想不到的地方
that Cuddy'll never look for me.
我还没发现我要找的东西
And I still haven't found what I'm looking for.
我这么跟你说吧  你再不走
Well, I can tell you, what you're about to find
我就用脚上你屁股了
is my foot in your ass.
我觉得我们没有足够的润滑油干这事吧
I don't think we've got enough lotion for that.
你怎么进来的啊  门明明锁了
How did you even get in here? The door was locked.
要么我能穿墙而过  要么...
Well, either I can walk through walls, or...
有发现了
We have liftoff.
这是卡迪的日记吗
Is that Cuddy's journal?
不  是我写给少女版时尚杂志的稿子
No, it's a freelance piece I'm writing for Teen Vogue.
别  别关  让我看看
No, no, no. Let me see that.
抱歉啦  我得走了
Sorry, got to go.
钥匙还我
Key.
还有件事要跟你说  豪拉尼
I got to give you one thing, Hourani.
你老婆  真是漂亮
Your wife, she's beautiful.
太惊艳了
I mean, wow.
谢谢
Thank you.
豪斯
House!
等一下
Wait.
我以为你就是豪拉尼医生啊
I thought you were Dr. Hourani.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
这就是你沦落至此的原因吗
So that's why you're here?
实在是够囧的
Well, that was stupid.
我知道
I know.
囧囧先生听候您的吩咐
Mr. Stupid-Head at your service.
-你在哪儿呢  -校长办公室
- Where are you now? - In the principal's office.
豪斯  没时间开玩笑了
House, we don't have time for games.
-正子扫描显示不是结节病  -太好了
- Pet scan was negative for sarcoidosis. - Great.
说明治疗起作用了
Means the treatment's already working.
如果确实开始治疗的话  你可以这么说
It would if we'd actually started the treatment,
-但我们没有  -为什么没有呢
- but we didn't. - Why the hell not?
因为不是结节病
Because it's not sarcoidosis.
你自己来看看就会知道了
If you were here, you would know that.
他快不行了
He's dying.
他的肺的剩余部分也在衰竭
What's left of his lung is collapsing.
-纵膈穿刺活检  -我不管活检结果如何
- F.N.A. of the mediastinal... - I don't care about the F.N.A.
我只关心他对治疗的反应
What I care about is how he responds to the treatment.
-豪斯  -按我说的做
- House. - Just do it.
结节病
Sarcoidosis...
属于已被排除的诊断
is a diagnosis of exclusion,
也就是说那些蹩脚医生费时费力
which means that the cowards who spend their time
不过是把不会导致病人死亡的病
excluding what it isn't usually cause their patients
从可能的病因中排除
to die from what it is.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你为什么用别人的名字啊
Why would you lie about your name?
谁在意那个  她的日记里写了什么
Who cares? What did she write in her journal?
谢谢
Thank you.
这才是我最在乎的
That is exactly my point.
怎么就没人相信我呢
Why does no one ever believe me?
什么啊
What?
他快死了这点并没让这个病例变得有趣
Just because he's dying doesn't make it interesting.
你背着她有人了  是不是
You cheated on her, didn't you?
没有  我没背叛她
No, I didn't cheat on her.
肯定不仅仅是因为你乱用她的牙刷
It's obviously more than just you used her toothbrush
然后还不倒垃圾
and wouldn't take the garbage out.
不  事实上  原因正是如此
No, actually, it was exactly that.
我想要一个人静一静
I just need some time alone.
就因为我用了你的牙刷吗
Because I used your toothbrush?
而且你还不把垃圾带出去
And you wouldn't take out the garbage.
这太扯了
That's insane.
你也这么觉得  不是吗
You know that, right?
你总是任意妄为  一直这样
You do whatever you want, always.
我说了我很抱歉  我...
I said I was sorry. I was...
我当时还没睡醒  没仔细听
I was still half asleep. I wasn't paying attention.
而真理总是在你这一边
And you're always right.
不是说你自认为自己是对的
And I don't mean you always think you're right.
而是你确实总是对的
But y-you are actually always right,
因为是非对错是你唯一关心的
because that's all that matters.
你这话毫无逻辑
That doesn't even make sense.
你想让我犯错吗
What, you want me to be wrong?
我是希望  你除了自己的一亩三分地
I want you to care about more than just what you want,
还能关心点别的
what you think.
你需要我  豪斯
You need me, House.
你甚至也许是爱我的
And you may even love me.
但你并不关心我
But you don't care about me.
而我需要能真正关心我的人
And I deserve someone who does.
所以我说对了
That's what I said.
你不在意她说的话
You don't listen to her.
你没说过
You didn't say that.
不  我说过
Yes, I did.
那就是我没仔细听
Well, I wasn't listening, then.
但你找到挽回这段感情的方法了  是吗
But you found a way to fix things, right?
所以你看到她本本里的内容时  很高兴
That's why you were happy when you read her laptop.
我的确找到了
I did.
至少我自己这么觉得
At least I thought I did.
最近  她收到了幼儿园的录取通知
She recently got the thin envelope
是她的首选幼儿园
from her first choice preschool.
但实际上  那家并不是她真正的首选
But it turns out it was her fake first choice,
因为她觉得  如果没有一笔可观的赞助费
'cause she was convinced she couldn't get her kid
或者走后门
into her actual first choice
她的孩子是进不了最中意的学校的
without a substantial donation or an inside connection.
如果是指布瑞学园  恐怕她是对的
If it's Brye Park, I'm afraid she's right.
等下  那是我们的学校
Wait, that's our school.
不然还是在说其它学校吗
What other school would he be talking about?
你赶紧接着讲完
Just finish the story.
我这么跟你说
You know, I got to tell you--
御姐气质有时是很性感
there is bossy, which can be sexy.
但过头了就令人反感...
And then there's bitchy...
少废话  接着讲完
Finish the story.
你很清楚这点
You obviously know this because
因为你是学校董事会成员
you're on the school board,
也就是说你有内部关系
which puts you on the inside,
而你还是这里的首席执行官
and being the CEO here
和卡迪之间也有来往
obviously connects you with Cuddy.
如果我们关系密切
Well, if we're so connected,
为何不是她在跟我说这些呢
why isn't she the one asking?
因为她觉得这样做不好
Because she thinks it's wrong
不该通过关系来走后门
to use connections to cut in line.
我不这么认为
I don't.
-我也许能帮上忙  -太好了
- I might be able to help. - Fantastic.
但你也要出点力才行
But I could use a favor as well.
你在哪呢
Where are you?
我有点事情要处理
I needed to take care of something.
没有看到异物
It's not a foreign body.
你肯定是看漏了
You must have missed it.
如果继续进行成像
If we do any more imaging,
就要将放射物中毒也考虑到鉴别诊断中
we're gonna have to add radiation poisoning to the DDX.
我说了是结节病
I meant the sarcoidosis.
活体检查和c-ANCA检测都是阴性的
The biopsy and c-ANCA were both negative.
我们得做个肺部...
We're gonna have to do a pneumon...
没有吸毒或酗酒的迹象
No sign of drug or alcohol abuse.
他不吸烟不嫖妓不吸毒
He's not a smoker, a coal miner, or a potter
就是结节病
It's sarcoidosis.
给他用皮质类固醇和甲氨喋呤来治疗
Start him on corticosteroids and methotrexate.
如果有抗药性  而我们再给他用类固醇
If it's a drug-resistant bug, and we give him steroids
那他会死
He'll die,
不过听起来也不比现在的情况糟多少
which from the sound of it wouldn't be much worse.
你这个傻冒
You moron.
但你得给他看你的证件
But you have to show him your I.D.
还有保险单吧
and your insurance stuff.
你不能就光告诉他个假名吧
You can't just give him a fake name.
你什么都不用出示
You don't have to do anything.
这招在美国屡试不爽  我上次就这么干的
Last time I checked, this was still America.
当然  那是十年前了
Of course, that was ten years ago.
但你会赔钱给他  对吗
But you're gonna pay him, right?
毕竟这事是你的错
I mean, it was your fault.
黄灯不是停车信号
A yellow light does not mean stop.
我至多只有百分之二十的责任
It was, at the most, 20% my fault.
鉴于保险公司自动认定
Since insurance companies automatically put
追尾方全责
100% of the fault on the rear-ender,
我小小的谎言其实
my little lie was actually an effort
让事情更接近真相了一些
to achieve an outcome closer to the truth.
而且差一点儿就奏效了
And it would have worked, too,
都怪那些多事的小屁孩
if it weren't for those meddling kids.
我就是豪拉尼医生
I am Dr. Hourani.
那你刚刚为什么说另一个医生是豪拉尼
Then why did you say the other doctor was Hourani?
这姓氏很常见嘛
It's, uh-- it's a common name.
就像史密斯
It's like Smith...
黎巴嫩很多人姓这个
in Lebanon.
给我看看你的证件
Let me see your I.D.
我说过了  忘在另一条裤子口袋里了
I told you, I left it in my other pants.
是吗  我看就在这里
Really? 'Cause it looks like it's still in this pair.
把你的手拿开
Get your hands off me.
给我看你的证件
Give me your I.D.
-你停手  -给我看你的证件
- Hey, would you stop that? - Give me your I.D.
先生们
Gentlemen, please.
孩子们  冷静
Kids, stay calm.
给我看你的证件
Gimme your I.D.!
马上住手  孩子们  待在座位上
Stop this right now! Stay in your seats, kids.
冷静  回到座位上
Stay calm, you guys. Stay in your seats.
先生们  请注意场合
Gentlemen, please. This is not the time or place.
科温小姐  这里出什么问题了吗
Is there a problem in here, Ms. Corwin?
你怎么不直接走人
Why don't you just take off?
校长又不能打电话叫你家长来
It's not like the principal can call your parents.
没错  可是校长可以报警
No, but the principal can call the police
或者找叫他来帮忙的那个人
or the guy he's doing the favor for.
他女朋友一定会发现的
His girlfriend's obviously gonna find out.
他死定了
He's screwed.
-是我我就溜  -不  你不会的
- I'd bolt. - No, you wouldn't.
我会的
Yeah, I would.
不  你不会的
No, you wouldn't.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我想
I guess...
我不想通过这种方式吻你
I don't want to do it like this.
对不起  我不该那么大力气打球
Sorry for shooting the puck so hard
也不该打赌的时候使诈
and tricking you in the bet.
-你没使诈  -我有
- You didn't trick me. - Yeah, I did.
我给了麦迪逊《红色死亡左轮》的作弊码
I gave Madison a Red Dead Revolver cheat code
让她用绳子拌你
so she'd hit your foot with the rope.
我就知道你不可能赢我
I knew you couldn't beat me.
你说得对  只是
You're right. It's just...
我真的喜欢你
I really like you.
我相信你也是喜欢我的
And I'm pretty sure you like me too.
我不想再耍花样了
But I don't want to play any more games.
如果你想  你什么时候准备好了
When you want-- I mean, if you ever want to,
告诉我就好
just tell me you're ready,
还有
and, you know...
对不起
Sorry.
好样的
Well done.
他不总是那么浑的
He's not always a jerk.
你也一样
And neither are you.
她明显是喜欢你的
She obviously likes you.
别再用她牙刷  别再玩花样
Just stop using her toothbrush and stop playing games.
她还是会喜欢你的
She'll still like you.
她很强势
She's bossy...
但她通常都是对的
but she's usually right.
谢谢
Thank you.
豪斯医生  可以问你个问题吗
Dr. House, can I ask you a question?
你是疯了还是脑子不好使
Are you insane or just stupid?
有第三个选项吗
Is there a third option?
恐怕没有
Actually, I don't think there is.
对不起  我没在用脑子
I'm sorry. I-I just wasn't thinking.
我有动脑子  可想到的只是我自己
I mean, I was, but only about myself,
我这人常常只想到自己
which is apparently the way I am...
但也并不总是这样
Usually, not always.
我想向一个人证明这一点
And I need to convince someone of that.
所以你认为你可以通过找人走关系
And you think you can do that by getting someone
把她女儿送进我们学校达到目的
to pull strings to get her daughter into our preschool.
我跟桑福德·威尔斯谈过了
I spoke to Sanford Wells.
你可以报警
You can call the police.
告发我在交通事故中报假身份
You can turn me in for lying at the accident.
我相信德赖登先生已经报警了
Oh, I'm sure Mr. Dryden has already taken care of that.
收她女儿入学吧
Let her daughter in.
她是个好孩子  卡迪医生是位好母亲
She's a great kid, and Dr. Cuddy is a great mom.
她们会很适合贵校的
They'll fit in perfectly here.
我们接收她女儿入学
And how exactly does admitting her daughter
如何能证明你的无私呢
prove how unselfish you are?
你的行为看起来仍是为了自己
Seems like you're still doing it to help yourself,
而非助人
not anyone else.
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道我一定要做点什么
I just know that I need to do something.
我的生活不能没有她
I need her in my life.
你知道切实需要一个人的感觉吗
You know what it's like to actually need someone?
是的
Yes.
我知道
I do.
但我也知道负有责任的感觉
But I also know what it's like to have responsibilities.
你也该长大了
Maybe it's time you grew up.
豪斯医生
Dr. House...
你还有什么要说的吗
Is there anything you'd like to say?
我可以走了吗
Can I be excused?
只是食物而已
It's just food.
小到足以误入气管
Something small enough to go down the wrong pipe,
大到支气管灌洗也冲不出来
too big to get washed out by the bronchial lavage.
CT上显示不出来
Wouldn't show up on a C.T.
会引起慢性阻塞性肺病
But would cause the C.O.P.D.
对类固醇和抗生素皆无反应
And wouldn't respond to steroids or antibiotics.
准备给他做探查手术
Prep him for exploratory surgery
开赌局
and start the betting.
赌局
Betting?
我押豌豆  100块
I got a hundred bucks says it's a pea.
我很忙
I'm busy.
我知道
I know.
我是来道歉的
I just want to say that I'm sorry.
这话你该去跟桑福德·威尔斯说吧
Shouldn't you be saying that to Sanford Wells?
给五年级孩子讲职业生涯
A fifth-grade career day?
你以为自己搞得定吗
You really thought you could pull that off?
我以为是小事一桩
I figured, how hard could it be?
而且我想向你证明
And I wanted to prove to you
我在乎你  在乎你的需要
that I do care about your needs
还有瑞秋的
and Rachel's.
真的
I do.
所以你才把我的电脑也偷走
Is that why you also stole my computer?
是的
Yes, it is.
然后把它丢进垃圾桶
And then threw it in the trash?
没有丢  是轻轻放的
I did not throw it, I placed it,
我知道清洁工会发现
knowing that the janitor would find it
并且认出是你的  物归原主
and know it was yours and return it to you unharmed.
我是白痴
I'm a moron.
但这不意味着我不关心你
But that doesn't mean I-I don't care about you,
不想着你
that I don't think about you,
不希望你幸福
that I don't want you to be happy.
我错了  你是对的
I was wrong. You were right.
我可以做到更好
I can do better.
请你再给我一个机会
Just...give me a chance.
跟小孩子扮什么职业了
So what were you...
宇航员还是斗牛士
an Astronaut or a Bullfighter?
就是我自己
I was myself...
没太夸张
for the most part.
我知道你心里还乱着
I know you're still upset,
所以我就不烦你了
so I'm gonna...
等你静一静  想怎样都行
I'll leave you to--to deal with it however you want.
豪斯
House.
今晚想来我家吃晚饭吗
You want to come over for dinner tonight?
乐意之至
I'd love to.